Guide to the William Lloyd Scott papers, 1967-1979
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
William Lloyd Scott papers
1967-1979
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
William Lloyd Scott, 1915-1997
C0128
236 linear feet (293 boxes)
Contains records of Scott's career as a U.S. Congressman and Senator of Virginia from 1967-1979, including reports, bills, hearings, campaign materials, appointment books, voting records, correspondence, publications, photographs, video tapes, and congressional research materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by William L. Scott in 1978.
Biographical Information
William Lloyd Scott was a Republican politician from Virginia. After receiving a law degree from George Washington University, Scott began his career as a trial attorney with the U.S. Department of Justice in 1934-1961 and served in the U.S. Army during World War II. In 1961-1966 Scott became a private practitioner of law in Fairfax, Virginia. In 1966 he received the Republican nomination for Representative of Virginia's 8th congressional district, where he served from 1967-1973. After working as a Virginia delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1972, Scott won a seat in the U.S. Senate, where he served from 1973-79.
Throughout his career, Scott became affiliated with numerous professional and fraternal organizations. He was a Methodist by faith, a member of the American Bar Association by trade, and became a member of the American Legion, Forty and Eight, the Freemasons, the Shriners, and the Lions. Scott was a resident of Fairfax Station, Virginia, but was confined later in life to a nursing center in Fairfax, Virginia for Alzheimer's Disease, where he lived out his final years.
Scope and Content
Contains records of Scott's career as a U.S. Congressman and Senator of Virginia from 1967-1979, including reports, bills, hearings, campaign materials, appointment books, voting records, correspondence, publications, photographs, video tapes, and congressional research materials.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collection and Archives also holds many other collections on Northern Virginia politics and government.
Index Terms
Persons:
Scott, William Lloyd, 1915-1997.
Corporate Names:
United States. Congress. House.; United States. Congress. Senate.
Geographical Names:
United States--Politics and government.
Subjects:
Bills, Legislative.
Contents List
  - Personal and Staff Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Personal and Staff Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Personal and Staff Political (Box 3)
  - Personal and Staff Political (Box 4)
  - Personal and Staff White House - Executive Office (Box 5)
  - Personal and Staff - Office Administration (Box 6)
  - Personal and Staff - Office Administration (Box 7)
  - Personal and Staff - Office Administration (Box 8)
  - Personal and Staff - Office Administration (Box 9)
  - Personal and Staff - trip Books/Invitations (Box 10)
  - Personal and Staff - Invitations (Box 11)
  - Personal and Staff - Invitations, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Personal and Staff - Legislative, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Campaign (Box 14)
  - Campaign, 1971 - 1972 (Box 15)
  - Campaigns, 1927 Cont. - 1978 (Box 16)
  - Campaigns, 1963 - 1968 (Box 17)
  - Campaign Contributor Card Files - 1, 1968 - 1970 (Box 18)
  - Campaign Contributor Card Files - 2 (Box 19)
  - Audio - Visual Photos (Box 20)
  - Audio - Visual Photos, 1966 - 1968 (Box 21)
  - Audio - Visual Photos, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Audio - Visual Photos, 1970 - 1971 (Box 23)
  - Audio - Visual Photos, White House and Other Photos, 1972 - 1975 (Box 24)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1976 - 1978 (Box 25)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1967 - 1968 (Box 26)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1969 - May 1970 (Box 27)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1971 (Box 28)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1973 (Box 30)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1974 - 1975 (Box 31)
  - Audio - Visual Press Releases, 1976 - 1978 (Box 32)
  - Audio - Visual Misc. Press Activities (Box 33)
  - Audio - Visual Newsletter, 1973 - 1976 (Box 34)
  - Audio - Newsletter, Compilation, Distributions, 1976 Cont. - 1978 (Box 35)
  - Audio - Visual Audio Tapes 1 - 56, 1972 - 1973 (Box 36)
  - Audio - Visual Tapes 57 - Microfilm Motion Picture Film, 1967 - 1971 (Box 37)
  - Audio - Visual TV Slides Video Tape, 1969 (Box 38)
  - Audio - Visual Video Tape, 1971 (Box 39)
  - Slides Negatives (Box 39A)
  - Audio - Visual "Scott for Senate", 1972 (Box 39B)
  - Audio - Visual "Virginians for Scott" (Box 39C)
  - Audio - Visual "House of Representatives", 1972 (Box 39D)
  - Legislation, 1967, 1968, and 1970 (Box 40)
  - Legislation, 1969 (Box 41)
  - Legislation, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Legislation, 1972 (Box 43)
  - Legislation, Abortion - Impeachment, 1973 (Box 44)
  - Legislation, Abortion - Impeachment, 1973 (Box 44A)
  - Legislation, Israel Urban Renewal, 1973 (Box 45)
  - Legislation, American - Fire Control, 1974 (Box 46)
  - Legislation, American - Fire Control, 1974 (Box 46A)
  - Legislation, Forest - Labor, 1974 (Box 47)
  - Legislation, Labor - Public Works, 1974 (Box 48)
  - Legislation, Records - Veterans, 1974 (Box 49)
  - Legislation, Abortion - Clear Air, 1975 (Box 50)
  - Legislation, Abortion - Clear Air, 1975 (Box 50A)
  - Legislation, Coal - Hazardous, 1975 (Box 51)
  - Legislation, Health - Labor, 1975 (Box 52)
  - Legislation, Health - Labor, 1975 (Box 52A)
  - Legislation, Labor - Oil, 1975 (Box 53)
  - Legislation, Osha - trade, 1975 (Box 54)
  - Legislation, Transportation - WLS, 1975 (Box 55)
  - Legislation, Affirmative - Election, 1976 (Box 56)
  - Legislation, Energy - Korea, 1976 (Box 57)
  - Legislation, Labor - Penna. Ave, 1976 (Box 58)
  - Legislation, Labor - Penna. Ave., 1976 (Box 58A)
  - Legislation, Post Office - Space, 1976 (Box 59)
  - Legislation, Tax - WLS, 1976 (Box 60)
  - Legislation, Tax - WLS, 1976 (Box 60A)
  - Legislation, Agriculture - Clean Air, 1977 (Box 61)
  - Legislation, Consumer Energy, 1977 (Box 62)
  - Legislation, Consumer Energy, 1977 (Box 62A)
  - Legislation, Environment - Health, 1977 (Box 63)
  - Legislation, Environment - Health, 1977 (Box 63A)
  - Legislation, Housing - Labor, 1977 (Box 64)
  - Legislation, Labor - Land, 1977 (Box 65)
  - Legislation, National - Social, 1977 (Box 66)
  - Legislation, Spaying - WLS, 1977 (Box 67)
  - Legislation, Agriculture - Civil, 1978 (Box 68)
  - Legislation, Consumer - ERA, 1978 (Box 69)
  - Legislation, ERA - Guns, 1978 (Box 70)
  - Legislation, Health - Labor, 1978 (Box 71)
  - Legislation, Labor - Procedures, 1978 (Box 72)
  - Legislation, Labor - Procedures, 1978 (Box 72A)
  - Legislation, Small Taxes, 1978 (Box 73)
  - Legislation, Taxes - WLS, 1978 (Box 74)
  - Legislation, Daily Digest, 1977 - 1978 (Box 75)
  - Committees, 1967 (Box 76)
  - Committees, 1967 (Box 76A)
  - Committees, 1968 (Box 77)
  - Committees, 1969 (Box 78)
  - Committees, 1970 (Box 79A)
  - Committees, 1970 (Box 79)
  - Committees, 1971 (Box 80)
  - Committees, 1971 (Box 81A)
  - Committees, 1971 (Box 81)
  - Committees, 1972 (Box 82)
  - Committees, 1972 (Box 83)
  - Committees, 1972 (Box 84)
  - Committees, 1973 (Box 85)
  - Committees, 1973 (Box 86)
  - Committees, 1973 (Box 86A)
  - Committees, 1974 (Box 87)
  - Committees, 1974 (Box 87A)
  - Committees, 1974 (Box 88)
  - Committees, 1974 (Box 89)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, 1974 (Box 90)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, 1974 (Box 90A)
  - Committees, 1974 (Box 91)
  - Committees, 1974 (Box 91A)
  - Committees, 1975 (Box 92)
  - Committees, Judiciary, 1975 (Box 93)
  - Committees, Judiciary, 1975 (Box 94)
  - Committees, Judiciary, 1975 (Box 95)
  - Committees, 1975 (Box 96)
  - Committees, 1975 (Box 97)
  - Committees, 1975 (Box 98)
  - Committees, Finance, 1976 (Box 99)
  - Committees, 1976 (Box 100)
  - Committees, 1976 (Box 100A)
  - Committees, Judiciary, 1976 (Box 101)
  - Committees, 1977 (Box 102)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1977 (Box 103)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1977 (Box 104)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1977 (Box 105)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1977 (Box 106)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1977 (Box 107)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, 1977 (Box 108)
  - Committees, Judiciary, 1977 (Box 109)
  - Committees, Judiciary, 1977 (Box 109A)
  - Committees, Judiciary, 1977 (Box 110)
  - Committees, 1977 (Box 111)
  - Committees, 1977 (Box 112)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1978 (Box 113)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1978 (Box 114)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, (Panama Canal Treaty), 1978 (Box 115)
  - Committees, Foreign Relations/Aid, 1978 (Box 115A)
  - Committees, 1978 (Box 116)
  - Committees, 1978 (Box 117)
  - Constituents, 1967 -1968 (Box 118)
  - Constituents, 1967 -1968 (Box 118A)
  - Constituents, 1969 -1972 (Box 119)
  - Constituents, 1973 (Box 120)
  - Constituents, 1973 (Box 121)
  - Constituents, 1973 (Box 121B)
  - Constituents, 1973 (Box 122)
  - Constituents, 1973 (Box 122A)
  - Constituents, 1973 (Box 123)
  - Constituents, Watergate, 1973 (Box 124)
  - Constituents, Watergate, 1973 (Box 125)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (A - F), 1974 (Box 126)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (G - MH), 1974 (Box 127)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (MI - V), 1974 (Box 128)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (W - Z), 1974 (Box 129)
  - Constituents, Social Security, 1974 (Box 130)
  - Constituents, Watergate, 1974 (Box 131)
  - Constituents, Watergate, 1974 (Box 132)
  - Constituents, Watergate, 1974 (Box 132A)
  - Constituents, 1974 (Box 133)
  - Constituents, 1974 (Box 133A)
  - Constituents, Energy, 1974 (Box 134)
  - Constituents, 1974 (Box 135)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (A - F), 1975 (Box 136)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (G - M), 1975 (Box 137)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (N - WH), 1975 (Box 138)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (W/A - Z), 1975 (Box 139)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 140)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 140A)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 141)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 142)
  - Constituents, Positions (L - O), 1975 (Box 142A)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 143)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 144)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 145)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 146)
  - Constituents, 1975 (Box 147)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (A - G), 1976 (Box 148)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (H - RN), 1976 (Box 149)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (H - RN), 1976 (Box 149A)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (ROA - Z), 1976 (Box 150)
  - Constituents, Veterans (C - Z), 1976 (Box 150A)
  - Constituents, 1976 (Box 151)
  - Constituents, Positions (A - N), 1976 (Box 152)
  - Constituents, Positions (A - D), 1976 (Box 152A)
  - Constituents, Positions (M - W), 1976 (Box 153)
  - Federal Employees/Civil Service Retirees, 1976 (Box 153A)
  - Constituents, 1976 (Box 154)
  - Constituents, 1976 (Box 155)
  - Constituents, 1976 (Box 156)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 156A)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (A - H), 1977 (Box 157)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (A - H), 1977 (Box 157A)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (I - Z), 1977 (Box 158)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (I - Z), 1977 (Box 158A)
  - Constituents, Outgoing Letters (I - Z), 1977 (Box 158B)
  - Constituents, Veterans, 1977 (Box 159)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 160A)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 160)
  - Constituents, Positions (A - Z), 1977 (Box 161)
  - Constituents, Positions (A - Z), 1977 (Box 161A)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 162)
  - Missing, 1977 (Box 163)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 164)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 164A)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 165A)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 165B)
  - Constituents, 1977 (Box 165)
  - Social Security, (A - HP), 1977 (Box 166A)
  - Social Security, (HQ - SQ), 1978 (Box 166B)
  - Constituents, (H - JZ), 1978 (Box 167A)
  - Constituents, (A - J), 1978 (Box 167)
  - Constituents, (K - Z), 1978 (Box 168)
  - Constituents, Veterans (A - Z) Military (L - Z), 1978 (Box 169)
  - Missing, 1978 (Box 170)
  - Constituents, Academy Appointments, 1978 (Box 171)
  - Constituents, Academy Appointments, 1978 (Box 171A)
  - Constituents, Academy Appointments, 1978 (Box 171B)
  - Constituents, Academy Appointments, 1978 (Box 171C)
  - Constituents, Academy Appointments, 1978 (Box 172)
  - Constituents, Positions (A - Z), 1978 (Box 173)
  - Constituents, Positions (A - Z), 1978 (Box 173B)
  - Constituents, 1978 (Box 174)
  - Constituents, 1978 (Box 175A)
  - Constituents, 1978 (Box 175)
  - Departments, 71, 1967 (Box 176)
  - Departments, Agriculture - Labor, 1972 (Box 177)
  - Departments, HUD - Transportation, 1972 (Box 178)
  - Departments, 1972 (Box 179)
  - Departments, State, A - Defense, 1974 (Box 180)
  - Departments, State, A - Defense, 1974 (Box 180A)
  - Departments, Defense - Energy, 1974 (Box 181)
  - Departments, HEW - HUD, 1974 (Box 182)
  - Departments, Interior - Labor, 1974 (Box 183)
  - Departments, Transportation - Treasury, 1974 (Box 184)
  - Departments, State - Agriculture, 1975 (Box 185)
  - Departments, Agriculture - Defense, 1975 (Box 186)
  - Departments, Defense Energy, 1975 (Box 187)
  - Departments, HEW - Interior, 1975 (Box 188)
  - Departments, Justice and Transportation, 1975 (Box 189)
  - Departments, Transportation - Treasury, 1975 (Box 190)
  - Departments, State - Agriculture, 1976 (Box 191)
  - Departments, Commerce - Defense, 1976 (Box 192)
  - Departments, Defense - Energy, 1976 (Box 193)
  - Departments, Hew - Interior, 1976 (Box 194)
  - Departments, Interior - Justice, 1976 (Box 195)
  - Departments, Labor - Treasury, 1976 (Box 196)
  - Departments, State - Agriculture, 1977 (Box 197)
  - Departments, Commerce - Defense, 1977 (Box 198)
  - Departments, Defense, 1977 (Box 199)
  - Departments, Energy - HEW, 1977 (Box 200)
  - Departments, HUD - Labor, 1977 (Box 201)
  - Departments, Justice, 1977 (Box 202)
  - Departments, Transportation - Treasury, 1977 (Box 203)
  - Departments, State, A - Commerce, 1978 (Box 204)
  - Departments, Energy - Housing, 1978 (Box 205)
  - Departments, Defense, 1978 (Box 206)
  - Departments, Interior - Justice, 1978 (Box 207)
  - Departments, Labor - Transportation, 1978 (Box 208)
  - Departments, Treasury, 1978 (Box 209)
  - Independent - Agencies, 1968, 1969, 1971, and 1973 (Box 210)
  - Independent - Agencies, 1973 Continued (Box 211)
  - Independent - Agencies, 1974 (Box 212)
  - Independent - Agencies, Appalachian - FTC, 1975 (Box 213)
  - Independent - Agencies, GAO - Veterans, 1975 (Box 214)
  - Independent - Agencies, Appalachian - Federal Reserve, 1976 (Box 215)
  - Independent - Agencies, FTC - Postal, 1976 (Box 216)
  - Independent - Agencies, Railroad - WMATC, 1976 (Box 217)
  - Independent - Agencies, Appalachian - Interstate, 1977 (Box 218)
  - Independent - Agencies, Library - WMATC, 1977 (Box 219)
  - Independent - Agencies, 1978 (Box 220)
  - Virginia, 1967, 1969, and 1972 (Box 221)
  - Virginia, Correspondence - General, 1973 (Box 222)
  - Virginia, Governor - Transportation, Agriculture - Bicentennial, 1973 and 1974 (Box 223)
  - Virginia, Consumer - Welfare, 1974 (Box 224)
  - Virginia, Agriculture - Legal (Box 225)
  - Virginia, Legislature - Welfare, Arlington - Corrections, 1975 and 1976 (Box 226)
  - Virginia, Education - Welfare, 1976 (Box 227)
  - Virginia, 1977 (Box 228)
  - Virginia, 1978 (Box 229)
  - Sealed Material, Do Not Open -- Common Cause -- Permission Required (Box 230)
  - Duplicate Material Filed Elsewhere (Box 231)
  - Duplicate Material Filed Elsewhere (A-V Video Tapes 79 and 80 copies 3 - 6) (Box 232)
  - Misc: Government Sentiment, etc..., 1977 (Box 233)
  - Misc: Government Sentiment, etc..., 1977 (Box 234)
  - Misc. (Box 234A)
  - Voting Records (Box 235)
  - Voting Records (Box 236)
  - Voting Records (Box 237)
  - Voting Records (Box 238)
  - Voting Records (Box 239)
  - Voting Records (Box 240)
  - Voting Records (Box 241)
  - Voting Records (Box 242)
  - Voting Records (Box 243)